你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
-这感觉不一样了  是吧  -什么
- This feels different, doesn't it? - What does?
作为已婚夫妇一起赶到犯罪现场
Rolling up to a crime scene as a married couple.
我们就像是尼克和诺拉·查尔斯那样的侦探夫妻
We're like Nick and Nora Charles.
或者是《麦克米伦夫妇》
Ooh, like "McMillan & wife."
-《哈特夫妇》  -《福星与福将》
- "Hart to hart." - "Turner & hooch."
福星和福将又不是夫妻
Turner and Hooch aren't even married.
是啊  但我还是觉得你有点像福将[狗]
Yeah, but you still remind me a little of hooch.
早间咖啡
So, uh, morning blend?
-这是刚刚发生的事吗  -嗯
- Did this just happen? - Yeah.
慢跑者大概一小时前发现他的
Jogger found him about an hour ago.
他也是那时候死的
Which was about the time he died.
不用说  死因很明显
Needless to say, - pretty obvious what killed him.
头部中枪
Gunshot wound to the head.
他是保罗·里夫斯  皇后区人
"Him" being Paul Reeves out of Queens.
我们正在查近亲
We're running down next of kin.
-有人听到枪声吗  -没有  公园这一带
- Anyone hear the shot? - No, and there's no video coverage
也没有监控
in this area of the park.
凶手大概知道
The killer probably knew that.
拿了里夫斯的手机和钱包里的现金
Took Reeves' phone, cash from his wallet,
然后大概大摇大摆走出去了
and probably waltzed right out of here.
看来是抢劫升级
Looks like a mugging gone wrong.
没有挣扎的迹象
Well, there's no signs of struggle.
如果是抢劫  他可没抵抗
If this was a mugging and he didn't put up a fight,
何必冒险在大白天开枪杀人
why risk shooting him, especially in broad daylight?
烧焦的布料
Singed fabric.
没人听到声音是因为凶手用了背包
Nobody heard anything because the killer used a backpack
或布闷住了枪声
or cloth to muffle the shot.
然后拿走了被害人的手机和钱迷惑我们
And then took the victim's phone and cash to throw us off track.
这不是抢劫
This wasn't a mugging.
是谋杀
This was a deliberate murder.
这说不通啊
That just doesn't make sense.
保罗完全没有敌人
Paul didn't have an enemy in the world.
你对你哥哥有多了解
Well, how much do you know about your brother's life?
-你们亲近吗  -很亲近
- Were you close? - Very close.
保罗最近一个月一直住在我那里
In fact, Paul had been staying at my place for the past month.
他在等待一间公寓第三方支付的完成
He was waiting to close escrow on a condo.
他常去公园喝咖啡吗
Was having coffee in the park something he did often?
他从不去中央公园
He never went to the park.
他几乎不离办公室
He hardly ever left the office.
保罗是个工作狂
Paul was a complete workaholic.
他是做什么的
And what did he do, exactly?
他是政府调查员  总审计局的
He was an investigator for the government, the G.A.O.
除此之外我就不清楚了
I don't know much more than that.
他不能多说工作上的事
He really couldn't discuss his job.
你知道他在单位遇到什么麻烦了吗
Was he having any troubles at work that you're aware of?
应该不算麻烦  但昨晚我们一起喝啤酒
Not trouble exactly, but...Last night, we had a beer.
保罗说有刚约了个重要的见面  很让他担心
Paul said a crucial meeting came up that he was worried about.
什么样的见面  跟谁
What kind of a meeting? I mean w-with whom?
他没说  但他接到了他一宗案件
He didn't say, but he'd got a disturbing call
涉及到的一个人的骚扰电话
from someone involved in one of his cases.
他说
And he said...
那个见面  好像就是在今早
That meeting... I think that was supposed to happen this morning.
抱歉  但如果他有约见面
I-I'm sorry, but if he had a meeting,
他也没跟我说过
he never mentioned anything to me,
不过这不算不寻常
Though I suppose that wasn't unusual.
我对他管得很松  保罗是我最好的调查员
I gave him a lot of latitude. Paul was my top investigator.
保罗究竟调查什么
What exactly did Paul investigate?
我们是联邦机构
We're a federal agency.
总审计局审核政府项目和合同
G.A.O. evaluates government programs and contracts
清除浪费  诈骗和滥用职权
to root out waste, fraud, and abuse.
比如国防部合同一个锤子要五百
Like defense contractors billing 500 bucks for a hammer.
是的  但保罗是医疗部的
Yes, though Paul - was in the healthcare division.
他监管有政府合同的
He oversaw hospitals and medical services
医院和医疗服务  这一类的
with government contracts... that sort of thing.
那么如果有人在骗政府的钱
So if someone was fleecing Uncle Sam,
他可以取消他们的合同
he could cancel their contracts?
他会写可能导致这事的报告  是的
He wrote reports that could produce that result, yes.
是否有人曾给保罗施压
Did anyone ever pressure Paul
让他停止哪个案子的调查
to back off a report or investigation?
不是那样的  我们是独立机构
It doesn't work that way. We're an independent body, so...
虽然如此
Be that as it may,
我们需要所有他正在进行中的调查的档案
we need the files of all his active investigations.
保罗·里夫斯有超过20件在查案件
Paul Reeves had over 20 open cases,
而且他调查的一些对象很有背景
and he was taking on some major players...
一家骗医疗保险的连锁医院
A hospital chain that defrauded medicare,
莱瑟姆制药一家实验室被报存储管理松懈
a-a lab at Latham Pharmaceuticals cited for lax storage practices,
还有一家售卖残次医疗用品的公司
and a company that sold the V.A. defective medical equipment.
我嗅到了浓浓的阴谋气息
I feel the heavy hand of conspiracy.
还有什么我不知道的
Yeah, well, what else is new?
想想  保罗揭露了一桩不法丑闻
Consider this... Paul uncovers a nefarious scandal
充斥着腐败和金融欺诈
rife with corruption and financial skullduggery
且与联邦合同有关
in connection with a federal contract,
但由于事关上百万美金  贪婪的承包商
but with millions of dollars at stake, the greedy contractor,
决心抓住联邦合同
determined to stay latched onto the federal teat,
便以见面为由引保罗去了公园
lures Paul into a meeting in the park
并雇凶在那里杀死了他
where he has an assassin silence him.
于是  保罗的发现便被永远埋没
Thus, Paul's findings never come to light.
那么你有猜到是保罗的
And I don't suppose that you have
哪件案子吗
a particular case of Paul's in mind, do you?
或者任何证据  嫌疑人
Or proof? Or suspects?
没有  但等你查明在公园见保罗的人是谁
No, but I will once you identify who met
我就会有理论了
Paul at the park.
我可能稍稍查到了一点
I might be a step closer to that.
还记得保罗的弟弟说
Do you remember how Paul's brother mentioned
那个见面是刚约的吗
that a "meeting" had just come up?
我查看了保罗手机过去48小时的通话记录
Well, I looked into Paul's phone calls for the last 48 hours.
其中一个很特别
One of them stood out...
昨天上午11点4分打去他办公室的一通电话
An incoming call to his office at 11:04 yesterday morning.
不到一分钟
Call lasted less than a minute,
经查是下东区一部付费电话打来的
And I traced it to a pay phone on the lower east side.
查查这通电话是谁打的
Try and find out who made that call.
嗯
Yeah.
这是那部电话的街头监控录像
This is street-cam video of the pay phone.
昨天上午11点4分
11:04 yesterday morning...
就是这人打给了保罗·里夫斯
This is the man who called Paul Reeves.
托瑞检索了图像  找到了匹配的人
Tory ran the image - and got a match on his face.
杰瑞德·斯通  电脑侵入轻罪
Jared Stone... misdemeanor computer trespassing?
俗称黑客
Otherwise known as hacking.
斯通曾是占领华尔街的积极分子
Stone was - an occupy wall street activist
他黑进一些大银行  公开了一些邮件
who hacked into a major bank, releasing their e-mails,
对他们的生意造成了影响
which reflected poorly on their business practices.
杰瑞德·斯通这样的黑客
So why would a hacker like Jared Stone
为什么要杀一个总审计局的调查员
kill a G.A.O. investigator?
他没有
He wouldn't.
这个逻辑说不通
That story doesn't make any sense.
但这个理论可以
But this one does.
凭借自己的黑客技术
Using his vaunted hacking skills,
杰瑞德·斯通发现了一桩不法丑闻
Jared Stone is the one who uncovered the nefarious scandal.
我们又回到不法丑闻上去了
So we're back to a nefarious scandal?
是的  他想揭发丑闻
Yes, see, he wants to blow the lid off a scandal,
那有什么比打电话给
so who better to call
无畏的调查员保罗·里夫斯更好的办法呢
than intrepid investigator Paul Reeves?
因为  杰瑞德·斯通是告密者
Because -- wait for it -- Jared Stone is a whistle-blower.
保罗·里夫斯被杀
And Paul Reeves was murdered
是因为他知道了杰瑞德·斯通发现的违法行径
because of what Jared Stone told him,
因此  杰瑞德现在也许有危险
which...which actually means he could be in danger now.
不得不承认   卡塞尔的推理
You have to admit, Castle's theory is...
很有逻辑
surprisingly logical.
对  而且恰巧毫无证据
Yes, and it's conveniently unburdened by evidence.
不管怎样  带杰瑞德·斯通来问话
Nevertheless, let's bring Jared Stone in for questioning,
同时去看下投币电话
and let's take a look at the video footage of that pay phone
过去两周的录像
for the past two weeks.
如果杰瑞德·斯通与人谈过  我要知道是谁
If Jared Stone talked to anyone, I want to know who it was.
我们可能查到他地址了
Yo, we may have an address on Jared Stone.
我刚查了他的邮件
I ran his e-mails.
他在信息网上租了间下西区的房
He rented a place on the lower west off Craigslist.
-行动  -收到
- Go. - Yeah, okay.
你的婚姻生活如何啊
So, what's going on with married life, huh?
家里还好吗
How is that -- the whole family thing?
我女儿长得太快了
Sarah Grace, she's -- she's growing up, changing so fast.
我想紧握她成长的每一刻
Just trying to hold on to every second.
你觉得我会是个怎样的父亲
Hey, what kind of dad do you think I'd be?
你会是个好爸爸的
You'd be great.
即使我自己没有榜样可参照吗
Even growing up with no role model?
但问题是
Well, you know, the thing of it is,
你知道没有父亲是什么感觉
is that you know what it's like not having a father.
所以你会确保你的孩子不会跟你一样
You'd make sure your kid never felt that way.
你和蕾妮
You and Lanie...Hmm?
不  她喜欢现状
No. She likes things how they are.
但是呢  或许我想要更多了
But, you know, maybe I'm ready for more than that.
-你懂吗  关系再向前一步  -明白
- You know what I'm saying? Move forward. - Huh.
你听见了吗  那声音
Hey, you hear that? That sound?
没有  什么声音
No. What sound?
我体内的生物钟在走
It's my biological clock ticking.
滴答  滴答  滴答
Tick, tock, tick.
我们在谈一件很正经的事
We were having a genuine, honest moment here,
你个混蛋却毁了一切
and you had to ruin it by being a jackass.
慢点慢点
Hold on, hold on. Slow down, slow down.
那是杰瑞德·斯通
That's Jared Stone.
等我一下
Hang tight here.
我去跟  确保他不会从我们眼皮下消失
I'll follow him on foot, make sure we don't lose him.
嘿  兄弟
Hey, bro.
我跟着他进了地铁
Yeah, I followed him down to the subway.
我在找他
I'm looking for him now.
什么  你跟丢了
What, you lost him?
不  我没有跟丢
No, I didn't lose him.
我只是暂时看不到而已
I just don't have visual contact.
这有差别吗
That's kind of splitting hairs, isn't it?
听着  我马上过来
Look, I-I'll head down there, and --
不不  你留在车里
No, no, no. You stay there.
等等  我看到他  他在我12点方向
I'll -- wait, I see him. He's at my 12.
他走得很快
Yeah, he's moving fast.
他看起来很慌张  好像有人跟踪他一样
He's scared, like someone's after him.
如果是真的  你最好在他们之前找到他
If someone is, you'd better get to him before they do.
杀死里夫斯也会对斯通灭口的
Whoever killed Reeves may be gunning for Stone.
他上了开往第七大道的车
He's boarding the 7th Ave. Express.
我跟着斯通上了地铁
All right, - I'm on the train with Stone.
你拿着一支没盖盖的马克笔
You're holding an uncapped marker,
你还告诉我你没打算在地铁上乱画吗
and you're telling me you were not about to tag this subway car?
对  不是这样的
Yes. I-I mean no.
出示身份证明
I need to see some identification.
我得给你开罚单
I'm gonna have to write you up for this.
杰瑞德·斯通  你好
Jared Stone? Hey.
你没惹上啥事  兄弟
You're not in trouble, bro, but, uh...
我只是来跟你了解下情况
Look, I'm just here to talk to you.
别动
Don't!
把你的枪扔地上
Put your gun on the ground!
快
Now!
把你的抢扔地上  快点
Put your gun on the ground now.
快
Do it.
把枪踢到我这边来
Kick it over to me.
往后退
Step back.
谁都别动
Nobody else move.
没人动  伙计
Nobody's moving, man.
我只是来跟你聊聊   我在你这边
All right, I just came here to talk to you. I'm on your side.
不  你是刀  是权贵的工具
No, you're a blunt instrument, a tool of the one percent.
听着  现在还没人受伤
Look, nobody's hurt yet,
所以我们可以当是误会一场
so this is - just a big misunderstanding.
你放下枪
So why don't you lower that weapon,
我们出去谈谈好吗
and we can walk right out of here?
-这可能吗  -相信我
- Oh, is that really possible? - It is, yeah.
你只需要把枪放下  杰瑞德
You just have to put the gun down, Jared.
那是什么  你开着电话
What the hell is that? Are you on the phone?
听着  所有人关掉电话  爬下
Everybody, shut off your phones and get the ground now!
哈维  哈维
Javi! Javi!
蹲着  别动  这样就没人会受伤
Stay down, don't move, and nobody gets hurt.
这不可能是真的
This cannot be happening.
别这样好吗
Please, look, don't do this.
别伤害我妻子
Okay? Don't hurt my wife.
还有我们
Or the rest of us. Let's be inclusive.
所有人保持冷静  别紧张
Hey, everybody just stay calm, all right?
我们会没事的
We're all gonna be fine.
听着  这里我说了算  不是你
Look, you're not in charge. I am.
我拉了紧急刹车
Hey, I pulled the emergency brake.
为什么列车长还没发起通话
Why hasn't the conductor come over the intercom yet?
-也许他   -闭嘴
- Well, maybe he--  - shh!
你感觉到了吗  有人在动
You feel that? That's movement.
像是乘客在紧急疏散
Like people are getting off the train, e-evacuating.
他们怎么知道的
How do they know?
你刚才在跟谁打电话
Who were you on the phone with?
一个朋友而已
Just a friend, man.
什么朋友  也是个警察吗
Oh, what kind of friend? Was it another cop?
是警察吗
Was it a cop, huh?
有必要的话我可以重拨
I can hit redial if I want.
是  他也是纽约警局的  但那不代表什么
Yeah, he was a -- he was NYPD, but that doesn't mean anything.
闭嘴
Okay, shut up.
所有人都闭嘴  好吧
Okay, everybody just stop talking, okay?
我得想想
I got to...Think.
他拿走了我的配枪
He took my service weapon.
我怎么能让他得逞
How did I let him do that?
这事可能发生在任何人身上  好吗
Hey, it could happen to anybody, okay?
我是哈维尔·埃斯波西托
I'm Javier, Javier Esposito.
梅丽莎·阿拉格
Marisa Aragon.
杰瑞德
Jared?
我能叫你杰瑞德吗
May I call you Jared?
我是格兰特·格博  推销员  我很善于倾听
Grant Gerber, salesman by trade, which means I'm a listener.
我会倾听并理解人们的需求  好满足他们
I listen and learn what people want so I can give it to them.
我来帮你吧  杰瑞德
Let me do that for you, Jared.
我想帮你得偿所愿
I want to help you get what you want.
你会有机会的
I think you'll get your chance.
我刚得知杰瑞德·斯通
I've just been informed that Jared Stone,
一个保罗·里夫斯案件的嫌疑人
a person of interest in the Paul Reeves case,
在地铁持枪挟持了人质
drew a gun on a subway and took hostages,
包括埃斯波西托警探
including detective Esposito.
目前还不清楚他为什么...
At this point, it's not clear why...
要说有谁能应付这种事  埃斯波绝对行
Hey, if anybody can handle it, Espo can.
也不知道他有什么打算
...or what his agenda is...
可斯通为什么要挟持人质
But why would Stone take hostages?
现在我们的首要目标就是
Right now our sole priority is to gather any
尽可能收集杰瑞德·斯通的相关信息
and all information on Jared Stone
以便人质救援小组
so the hostage-rescue team
了解对方的底细
will know who we're dealing with.
所有情报都给我  我会直接转达给人质救援小组
All intel comes to me so that I can forward it directly to HRT.
他们现在应该到现场了
They should be on the scene right now.
-莱恩警探吗  -是的  长官
- Detective Ryan? - Yes, sir.
我是比格罗队长  人质救援小组的
Captain Bigelow, HRT.
有什么疑犯的信息
What's your intel on your suspect?
长官  他是个黑客  是占领华尔街运动的激进分子
Sir, he's a hacker, an occupy wall street activist.
都是些笼统的信息
It's all sketchy.
你们的人埃斯波西托呢  我们能指望他吗
What about your boy Esposito? Is he someone we can count on?
-他可靠吗  -他非常可靠
- He's solid? - He's as solid as they get.
明白
Roger that.
贝克特  我很抱歉
Hey, Beckett. I'm sorry.
凯文  没人能预见到这种事
Kevin, no one could have seen this coming.
不不  他是我的搭档
No, no, he's my partner.
我就不该让他一个人进去
I should have never let him go in there alone.
我们得集中精力把哈维救出来
We got to focus on getting Javi out of there,
你跟救援组简报完就直接去斯通的公寓
So once you brief HRT, just head over to Stone's apartment.
离开现场吗
Leave the scene?
你能做的救援小组都已经在做了
There's nothing that you can do that HRT isn't already doing.
如果我们想救出哈维
And if we want to help javi out,
那我们能做的最大努力
then the best thing that we can do
就是查明杰瑞德·斯通的身份和动机
is find out who Jared Stone is and why he is doing this,
而线索很可能就在他的公寓里
and some of those answers might be at his apartment.
好吧  我会去查查  有消息通知你
Okay. I'll check it out and let you know.
凯特  他们说的是真的吗
Kate, is it true -- what they're saying?
听着  他经历过比这更糟的情况
Listen, he has been - in worse scrapes than this,
我们会救出他的  我保证
and we're gonna get him out of there, I promise you.
贝克特探长  帕里什医生
Detective Beckett, Dr. Parish,
我们看到埃斯波西托了
we've got eyes on Esposito.
这镜头是哪来的
Where's this coming from?
交管局应该没在地铁车辆上安装摄像头啊
I didn't think the MTA had cameras in the subway cars.
是没有
They don't.
这辆列车是安装安保监控的试点车辆
The train is part of a pilot program for video security.
在一个独立的信号
This is on a separate feed,
所以我花了点时间才找到
So it took me awhile to find it.
等等  如果这是独立的信号
Wait, if this is on a separate feed...
那就意味着我们能看到斯通  而他并不知道
that means that we can see Stone, but he doesn't know that.
那我们就有战术优势了
Which gives us a tactical edge.
我会确保救援小组知道这一情况
I'll make sure HRT knows about this.
起码哈维不是一个人在面对
At least Javi's not down there alone.
还有个警察跟他一起
There's another cop with him.
是啊  有他俩在
Yeah, between the two of them,
他们或许能缓和局面
they might be able to diffuse the situation.
他现在听音乐有点奇怪吧
Kind of a weird time for him to be hitting his playlist.
他是想让自己镇定下来
He's trying to calm himself down.
镇定下来要做什么
Because he's about to do what?
我可能需要你帮忙
I might need you to back me up.
你能行吗
Can you do that?
你有什么打算
What's your play?
跟他聊天  试着让他觉悟
Talk to him, try to get him to see the light,
如果有机会就卸下他的武器
then disarm him if I get the chance.
我去吧  穿警服的可是我
I should talk to him. I'm the one wearing the kevlar.
是  但我已经跟他搭过话了
Yeah, but I've already got a rapport with the guy, so...
那话可没搭好
A bad rapport.
我知道你什么意思  我只是个运输警
I know what this is. I'm just a transit cop.
你们这些警察
You gold-shield guys,
总觉得你们比我们强
always acting like you're better than us.
我们的确比你们强
We are better than you.
斯通先生
Mr. Stone?!
我能说话吗
Permission to speak?
说吧
Go ahead.
别再靠近了
That is far enough.
听着  不管你跟保罗·里夫斯之间发生了什么
Look, whatever went down between you and Paul Reeves,
这样只会让事情更糟
this is only gonna make it worse.
本来不该这样的  起码不是在这里
This wasn't supposed to happen -- not here.
这并非计划中的事
This wasn't part of the plan.
那我们可以想个新的计划
Then we can come up with a new plan,
能让你安全离开这里的计划
one where you walk out of here.
现在还来得及
You can still do that.
来不及了
It's too late.
警方已经介入了
Police are already involved.
我知道没有回头路了
It -- I know there's no turning back.
你必须回头  杰瑞德
You have to turn back, Jared,
你要是不回头  我跟你说说后果
'cause if you don't, - here's what's gonna happen.
HRT  也就是人质救援小组
HRT -- that's the hostage rescue team --
会跟你僵持到你开始疲软
Will wait for you to get weak and tired,
然后十多个训练有素  全副武装的家伙
then a dozen highly trained guys armed to the teeth
会冲进这辆车
Will breach this car.
相信我  他们可不是闹着玩的
And trust me when I tell you... They will not play.
你能一枪殒命就算运气好了
You'll be lucky to get off one shot before they drop you.
HRT不会靠近我的
HRT won't come near me...
只要他们知道我有这个
...Not once they know I have this.
天啊  人肉炸弹背心
Oh, my god, a suicide vest.
他左手  那是失知触动装置
His left hand. That's a dead man's switch.
如果他松手...
If he lets go of that...
很明显  杰瑞德·斯通不是告密者
Clearly, Jared Stone is not a whistle-blower.
他是个身穿炸弹背心的恐怖分子
He's a terrorist wearing an explosive vest.
这是一场有预谋的袭击
This was a planned attack.
我会联系国安局  看他们有什么信息
I'll contact Homeland, see what they have on him.
继续调查杰瑞德·斯通
Keep working intel on Jared Stone.
显然他不是我们想的那样
Obviously, the man is not at all who we thought he was.
杰瑞德  你在干什么
Jared, what are you doing, man?
不用我解释吧  不是吗
It's kind of self-explanatory, isn't it?
我知道你是激进分子
Look, I know you're an activist
你全力抵抗权贵阶级
and you're all about taking on the one percent,
你看这里有那样的人吗
but do you see anybody like that here?
我虽是个推销员
Look, I may be a salesman,
但是你要知道  我赚得并不多
but just so you know, I'm not a big earner.
我只是勉强度日
Okay, I am barely scraping by.
杰瑞德  这些都是跟你一样辛勤工作的人
Jared, these are - working people -- your people.
你不希望伤害他们的
You don't want to hurt them.
你说得对  我不想
You're right. I don't.
但如果迫不得以  我会的
But I will if I have to.
拍张照片  发给人质救援小组
Take a picture. Text it to HRT.
告诉我你知道的关于杰瑞德·斯通的所有事
I need you to tell me everything you know about Jared Stone.
只知道他只租两周
Just that he wanted the apartment for two weeks,
所以我租给他了
so I rented it to him.
你见过他吗  跟他说过话吗
Did you meet the guy, talk to him?
给钥匙的时候见过一次
Just when I gave him the key
我告诉他这里不允许开狂野派对
and told him I did not permit wild parties.
发生什么事了
What's this about?
搜查这里每一个角落
All right, comb through every inch of this place.
检查他所有的文件  个人物品
Look through all his papers, personal items,
任何信息  所有关于他身份和目的的线索
anything that can tell us who Jared Stone is or what he's up to.
抱歉  先生们
E-excuse me, gentlemen,
能要求你们把鞋脱掉吗
but could I ask you to remove your shoes?
地毯是新买的  只是说说
The carpet is brand-new. Just a thought.
谢谢你
Thank you.
国安局没有关于杰瑞德·斯通的文件
Homeland doesn't have a file on Jared Stone.
纽约警局的反恐档案里也没有
Neither does NYPD counter-terrorism.
斯通为什么要炸地铁
Why would Stone blow up the subway?
我在读他关于收入不平等的文章
I-I-I've been reading his posts on income inequality.
他有点迂腐  但只是纸上谈兵
He's a little pedantic, but he's an armchair revolutionary.
他并不是一个行动派
He's not a man of action.
也许有什么事让他变得激进了
Maybe he became radicalized somehow.
上演"地铁惊魂"不可能是他的计划
"The taking of Pelham 123" could not have been his plan.
他肯定是准备去什么地方
He must have been headed someplace else
埃斯波西托挡住了他的路
when Esposito stopped him.
没错
He was.
斯通准备去参加一个财富管理研讨会
Stone was set to attend a wealth-management seminar
有1500人参加  在特里梅因酒店举行
with 1,500 people at the Tremaine Hotel.
他准备去那里  可是埃斯波西托出现了
That's where he was going when Esposito came along.
七号线正好可以到达那里
The 7th avenue express would have taken him right there.
如果他是要对付权贵
And if he was after one-percenters,
这研讨会可满满都是目标
this seminar would be a target-rich environment.
长官  他还有个后备目标
Sir, he also had a backup target.
他订了一张歌剧的票
He had seats to an opera
在百老汇最大的剧院  有1900个座位
at the biggest theater on Broadway -- 1,900 seats.
他想要的是大规模伤亡
He was going for maximum casualties,
而且想要与这些人同归于尽
and he's willing to kill himself in the process.
我把这些转告人质救援小组  还有一件事
I'll pass this on to HRT. Oh, uh, one more thing.
托瑞查了那个投币电话
Tory ran video on that pay phone.
斯通以前用过
Stone did use it before.
他上周往马尔代夫打过两次电话
He called the Maldives last week twice.
马尔代夫
The Maldives?
他打电话给谁
Who was he talking to?
他打的那个手机已经停用了
The cellphone he has is no longer active.
追踪不到
Can't track it down.
盖茨
Gates.
人质救援小组那面问
HRT is asking,
"埃斯波西托喜欢什么味的披萨"
"What kind of pizza does detective Esposito like?"
菠萝  橄榄  双份墨西哥胡椒  长官
Uh, uh, pineapple, olives, and, uh, double jalapeno, sir.
我会转达的  菠萝
I'll pass it along. Uh...Pineapple...
作为一个黑客
Since when does a hacker,
他应该是生活在网上
who by his very nature tends to live his life virtually,
怎么会变成人肉炸弹客了呢
morph into a suicide bomber?
斯通没有暴力史
Stone has no history of violence.
你认为有什么事触动了他吗
You think something happened to trigger him?
我不知道  但是这里似乎漏掉了什么
I don't know, but there's a piece missing here somewhere.
总审计局的调查员与这事什么关系
H-how does a G.A.O. Investigator fit into this?
打去马尔代夫的电话
The calls to the Maldives?
莱恩那面有消息吗
Has Ryan turned anything up?
目前为止还没有
No, so far, no word.
请问一下
Excuse me.
这张两天前的碎纸机收据
This receipt from two days ago for the shredder --
-是你买的吗  -不是
- Did you buy it? - No.
我不知道从哪来的
I don't even know where that came from.
和这里不搭
It really doesn't fit.
是斯通买的
Then Stone bought it.
不好意思  你能...
Excuse me. Could you...
他在粉碎文件
He's shredding documents.
把这些都装起来
Okay, we need to bag this up
带回分局去
and take it back to the precinct,
把它们拼起来  找出斯通在隐藏什么
put it back together, find out what Stone was trying to hide.
你是怎么找到我的
So, how did you find me?
你怎么追踪到我的
How did you track me down?
你知道白色骑士吗
Do you know about white knight?
什么白色骑士
What's white knight?
肯定是谈判专家
That'll be the negotiator.
你有所需求  不是吗
You want something, right?
现在是你提出要求的时候了
Now would be the time to ask for it.
你好
Hello?
是的  我是
Yes, I-it is.
你好  鲍勃  你是谈判专家
Hello, Bob. You're the negotiator?
我很好
I'm fine.
是的  他们也很好
Yeah, yeah, th-th-they're all fine, too.
我问一下  谁饿了吗
Uh, let me ask. Is, uh, anybody hungry?
-我总在饿  -我也是
- I'm always hungry. - So am I.
大家现在
Yeah, um e-everybody could use
都想吃东西
some food right about now. Um...
你去做吧  鲍勃
Well, you do that, Bob.
需求
Demands.
我有需求吗
Do I have demands?
是的
Yeah.
我有一个
I got one.
你在听吗
You listening?
我要监狱释放艾伦·威尔逊
I want Aaron Wilson released from prison.
有了完成此事的计划再给我回电
You call me back when you have a plan to make that happen.
这就完了
That's all he said?
艾伦·威尔逊又是谁啊
Who the hell is Aaron Wilson?
如果我们想救这些人  就得找出答案
Well, if we want to save these people, we need to find out.
查查艾伦·威尔逊是谁吧
Okay, let's find who this Aaron Wilson is.
等等
Wait a minute.
卡塞尔  是个女人  是艾琳
Castle, it's a woman -- E-R-I-N.
她因为电脑侵入重罪
She's serving seven years in federal prison
被判入狱服刑七年
for felony computer trespassing.
她也是个黑客
So she's a hacker, too.
庭审记录说她入侵了
Court records show that she hacked a database
纽约美联储的数据库
at the New York Federal Reserve,
寻找美联储和各大银行勾结的证据
looking for proof that the Fed colluded with the big banks.
她和斯通什么关系呢
What's her connection to Stone?
杰瑞德·斯通好像是从犯
It looks like Jared Stone was an accomplice,
但美国检察院没有足够证据起诉他
but the U.S. Attorney didn't have enough to charge him.
他们是犯罪伙伴
So they were partners in crime.
艾琳进了监狱  斯通却没有
Erin went to prison, Stone didn't.
所以他想救她出来
That's why he wants to get her out.
他觉得愧疚
He feels guilty.
这也解释了打去马尔代夫的电话
That would also explain the Maldives.
-什么意思  -一个无引渡条约的国家
- What do you mean? - It's a non-extradition country.
两位  过来看看这个
Hey, guys, you need to see this.
碎纸机里大概有两页文本
What was in that shredder was about two pages of text.
目前为止  我们只拼出了几个零碎的词
So far, we've been able to assemble a few random words,
有监视器  监控
like "Monitor" And "Surveillance."
那你觉得这是什么
Okay, what do you think it is?
好像是封信
It's some kind of letter,
但我觉得不是斯通写的
but I don't think that Stone was the one who wrote it.
看看我们刚拼出的这个句子
Take a look at this phrase that we assembled just now.
阅读  记忆  然后销毁
"Read, memorize, and then destroy"?
应该不是他写给自己的
It's not like he would write that to himself.
所以这是指令
So they're instructions.
现在我们知道斯通还有同谋
Now we know Stone - is working with other people.
也许这些都与艾琳·威尔逊有关
Maybe this is all about Erin Wilson.
也许她就是幕后主使
Maybe she's the one behind all this.
卡塞尔和我会跟进深入调查艾琳·威尔逊
Castle and I will look into Erin Wilson and dig deeper,
也会找找杰瑞德还有没有
and we'll also see if we can identify any associates
其他已知同伙
that Jared might have had.
我们会继续拼这个
We'll keep piecing this together here.
伙计们  被劫持的人都指望着我们呢
Guys, everyone down there is counting on us.
艾琳·威尔逊是谁
Who's Erin Wilson?
我的灵魂伴侣
She's my soul mate.
你应该多给鲍勃提供点信息
Well, why not give Bob more to go on
好让他知道你说的是谁
so he knew who you were talking about?
不想让他知道太多  我要控制局面
I want to keep him off-balance, maintain control.
你这是网上看来的建议吗
You get that tip off the internet?
这建议真烂
'Cause it's not a very good one.
白色骑士是什么
What's White Knight?
告诉我你释放艾琳的计划
Tell me your plan for Erin.
你怎么用了这么久  鲍勃
What the hell is taking so long, Bob?
抓她进监狱  可比放出来快多了
Getting her in prison didn't seem to take any time at all!
鲍勃  闭嘴
D-- Bob, shut up!
闭嘴
Shut up!
听我说
Listen to me.
我要你们送她坐飞机去马尔代夫
I want her flown to the Maldives.
那我现在告诉你  鲍勃
Yeah, well, I'm telling you now, Bob.
好吧
Okay.
我要你们送她坐飞机去马尔代夫
I want her flown to the Maldives,
半小时后  我要你关于此事的计划
and in half an hour, I want your plan on how to make that happen.
听懂了吗
Are we clear?
鲍勃  送点食物来  是个好主意
Yeah, Bob, food would be great right about now.
不  不许派警察来
No. Don't send any cops.
我不管他们有没有武器  鲍勃
I don't care if they're unarmed, Bob!
我不要警察接近这里
I don't want any police near this car!
把食物放下就行
Just drop the food!
那就放在站台边上
Then set it on the edge of the platform!
我派人去取
I'll send somebody to get it.
你  她丈夫  你去取
You, the husband, go. Get the food.
我确定你会回来
I know you'll come back.
坏消息
I just got bad news.
我打去监狱和艾琳·威尔逊谈了
I called the prison and spoke to Erin Wilson.
然后呢
And?
她是斯通的女友  但她好像
She's Stone's girlfriend, but she didn't seem to know
直到刚刚  才知道他想要救她出去的计划
about his plan to break her out until just now.
你呢  找到斯通已知同伙的线索了吗
What about you? Anything on Stone's known associates?
斯通虽然天天挂在网上  但社交很少
Stone may have lived online, but he wasn't very social.
他办了一个释放艾琳·威尔逊的网页
He started a "Free Erin Wilson" website
但好像并未和其他用户有联系
but didn't seem to interact with any other users.
肯定有人和他联系了
He had to have interacted with somebody.
技术组仔细搜查了他的电脑
Tech scrubbed his computer and
发现了一个隐藏目录
found a hidden directory
他们认为里面是秘密通讯
that they think contained private correspondence.
-和谁的  -内容完全被删除了
- From whom? - The contents were thoroughly erased.
剩下的只有
The only thing that was left
目录的名字  白色骑士
was the name of the directory -- "White knight."
下一个是谁
Okay, who's next?
双份芝士  意大利辣肠加蘑菇
We got double cheese, pepperoni, mushroom.
这里  谢谢
Uh, right here. Thanks.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You doing okay? - Yeah.
加茄子大蒜的素食披萨
Veggie with eggplant and garlic.
菠萝  橄榄  双份墨西哥胡椒
Pineapple, olives, double jalapeno.
-是我的  -真的假的啊
- That's for me. - Really?
我们被困在一节地铁车厢
We're trapped in a subway car.
我觉得你还是不吃为好
I'm not sure you should eat that.
你是打算吃它  还是和它深情对视
You gonna eat that thing, or just gaze at it in wonder?
我不明白  人质救援小组为什么要突击
I don't understand. Why does HRT want to breach?
经他们评估  斯通被困此处
In their assessment, Stone is trapped,
没有好的选择  也不能继续原本的计划
with no good options and no way to carry out his original plan.
他们认为拖得时间越久
They believe the longer this goes,
他越有可能做出鲁莽举动
the more likely he will do the unthinkable.
那为什么不从释放艾琳·威尔逊那边下手
Well, why not see how things play out with Erin Wilson?
救援小组认为艾琳·威尔逊只是幌子
HRT thinks the Erin Wilson demand is a ruse,
斯通提这要求是为了拖延时间
Stone is playing this card to buy time,
慢慢鼓起勇气
work up his nerve.
突击的话  怎么保证斯通不会引爆呢
If they bust in, what'll keep Stone from blowing that vest?
埃斯波西托  他会参与行动
Esposito will. He's in on it.
斯通难道不会看到救援小组吗
Won't Stone see HRT coming?
有可能  如果他们从隧道接近的话
Yes, if they approach via the tunnel,
但他们打算通过地铁护栏
but they're dropping onto the train from above,
从车厢上方接近
through the subway grates.
什么时候
When?
马上
Soon.
随时都有可能
Any moment now.
你确定我们不告诉其他人
You sure - we shouldn't tell the others?
不能说
No.
他们会紧张  那样斯通就会察觉
They'll get nervous, and Stone will pick up on it.
你为什么当警察
Hey, why did you become a cop?
我退伍之后这是最合理的选择
I got out of the army. It's what made the most sense.
我也是
Me too.
你怀念当兵的生活吗
You miss the service?
怀念其中一部分
Some parts.
其他就一点都不怀念
Not others.
结婚了吗  有孩子吗
Married? Kids?
没有  别这样  好吗
No. Don't do this, okay?
不要分散我的注意力
Don't try to take my mind off of what's coming.
我不需要别人握住我的手
I don't need anyone holding my hand.
你知道吗  你看上去非常紧张
You know, you got a chip on your shoulder
有点暴躁
the size of stonehenge.
我只是想多了解你一点
I was just trying to get to know you a little bit.
-看到那个了吗  -当然
- You see that? - Sure did.
再闪一下我们就行动
The next flicker is go time.
-你对计划清楚了吗  -别担心我了
- You clear on the plan? - Don't worry about me.
我感受到振动了  他们在车上
I can feel vibrations. They're on the train.
赶紧叫你的人撤退  否则大家都得死
You pull your people back now or everybody dies.
立刻
Now!
我知道他们在这
I know they're here!
别耍我  鲍勃
Don't screw with me, Bob,
否则我现在就拉动开关
or I will pull my hand off this trigger right now!
我怎么相信他们都走了呢
How am I supposed to trust they're gone, huh?
你刚才派了突击队
You just tried to send storm troopers
在不知道他们和我在哪儿的情况下
into a subway car full of people,
冲进一节载满客的地铁车厢
not knowing where they are or where I am...
等等
Wait a second.
别担心  他会没事的
Don't worry. He's gonna be okay.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
她怎么样
How is she?
至少她看到了哈维  知道他没事
Well, at least when she could see Javi, she knew he was okay.
我们会把埃斯波救回来的
We'll get Espo back.
关键是要找出斯通的同伙
The key is finding out who Stone was working with.
答案可能就在那个白衣骑士的目录里
The answer's probably in that white knight directory.
但目前为止  技术部还没能复原任何数据
But so far, but tech hasn't been able to recover any of the data.
那我们再去看看被害人
Well, then, we'll revisit the victim.
查看保罗·里夫斯的调查
Looking into Paul Reeve's investigations
引领我们找到了斯通
is what led us to Stone.
也许它还能帮我们找到其他人
Perhaps it'll lead us to the others, as well.
托瑞  我问你些事
Tory, let me ask you something.
地铁里的监控
Uh, t-the video from the subway --
在被切断之前  你录下来了吗
before it cut out, did you record it?
当然  所有的视频流都会自动归档
Of course. All streaming video is archived automatically.
怎么了
Why?
你能放给我看吗  有点东西我想看看
Could you show it to me? There's something I'd like to see.
这些都是保罗·里夫斯
These are all 20 of the case files
调查的20份案子文件
Paul Reeves was working on.
这是所有案子的概述
Here's just a summary of those cases.
我想我们只要找到
I figure we just go through these
关于斯通  艾琳·威尔逊
until something points to Stone or to Erin Wilson
或者其他有关人就行
or anything else we're dealing with.
好的  我先开始
Okay. I'll start.
第一个是关于制药实验室
Uh, the first one is that pharmaceutical lab
丢失流感病毒样本
cited for losing samples of a flu virus.
没想到什么
Not ringing any bells.
下一条是关于药品供应链
Moving on to a medical chain
故意植入有缺陷的人工髋关节
that knowingly implanted defective artificial hips.
伙计们  那个文件  我觉得是参照样本
Hey, guys, that document -- I think it's a playbook.
斯通所作所为都是照着上面的话
Stone's following it to the letter.
看看这些句子的片段
Take a look at this sentence fragment.
要求艾琳·威尔逊被释放  然后挂电话
"Demand Erin Wilson's release from prison, then hang up."
还有别的指示吗
More instructions?
我是说这貌似没有提供我们不知道的细节
I mean, how is that telling us anything we don't already know?
你会明白的  现在看看这个
You'll see. now take a look at this one.
要求送艾琳坐飞机一个没有引渡条约的国家
"And demand Erin be flown to a non-extradition country."
但在文件里那条指示出现在后面
But that instruction comes later on in the document,
斯通也完全按照上面的指示来行动的
which is exactly how Stone played it.
首先他要求释放她
First, he demanded her release,
然后又提到了马尔代夫
and then he brought up the Maldives.
这说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
如果斯通想让艾琳·威尔逊从监狱释放出来
If Stone wanted Erin Wilson freed from prison,
为什么他后来才提到马尔代夫呢
then why would he wait to mention the Maldives until later?
基于同样原因  他提出释放艾琳·威尔逊
For the same reason he asked about Erin Wilson's release
却没有说她是谁
without explaining who she was.
斯通在拖延时间  他在争取时间
Stone is stalling. He's playing for time.
还有其他的事情  很严重的事
Something else is going on here, something big.
凯特  我得让你看点东西
Kate, I need to show you something.
我之前看录像的时候注意到了一些细节
I noticed something when I was watching earlier,
所以我就重新看了整个录像
so I went to watch this whole video.
我们遇到了问题  一个新问题
We have a problem -- a new problem.
这是斯通
This is Stone
当他把他们当做人质的时候
back when he was just holding them all hostage.
这是他后来的样子  再后来
This is him later... And later.
他的哮喘越来越严重
His asthma's getting worse.
不仅仅是哮喘而已
It's not just his asthma.
看上去他好像发烧感冒了
It looks like he has fever and chills.
他不能清晰思考  只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time before he's not able to think clearly.
他生病了
The man is sick,
而且流感的病征越来越严重
and he's getting sicker with flu-like symptoms.
流感的病征
Flu-like symptoms?
卡塞尔  那个案子
Uh, Castle, that case.
保罗·里夫斯调查了一起流感病毒的丢失案
Paul Reeves was investigating a missing flu virus.
现在这些都是有关联的了
This is all connected somehow.
一定是有关联
It has to be.
当我得知她上了国际航班
Once I hear that she's in international airspace,
我就会投降
I'll surrender.
因为我给了你承诺
Because I'm giving you my word.
斯通看上去不太好
Stone's not looking too good.
到底还要多久才能办到
Hey, exactly how long is that gonna take, huh?
如果他晕过去松掉开关  我们都会死的
If he passes out and releases that switch, we're all dead.
-我们得采取行动  -鲍勃  那
- We got to make a move. - Bob, bob, bob, that's...
-还是之前的计划吗  -我不能接受  -是的
- The same plan as before? - That's not acceptable. - Yeah.
什么时候
When?
当他吸药分心的时候
He gets distracted when he puffs on his inhaler.
下一次  我们就行动
Next puff, we go.
听着  那就是我的条件
Look, those are my conditions.
一旦我知道艾琳被释放
Once I hear from Erin that she's free,
我发誓  我会放所有人走的
I swear, I'll let everybody go.
大家别担心
Don't worry, everyone.
这一切就快结束了
It's almost over.
不  别
No, stop!
-求你了  -保护好起爆器
- Please! - Secure the switch.
我的任务还没完成  任务还没有完成
I'm not done yet! I'm not done yet!
快  快  快  快
Go, go, go, go.
好样的
Good job.
哈维
Hey, Javi.
怎么样  我们把斯通拿下了
What's up? We took down Stone.
没人受伤  大家都很好  都结束了
Nobody's hurt. Everybody's fine. It's over.
并没有结束  伙计
It's not over, man.
什么  什么叫还没有结束
What? What do you mean, it's not over?
虽然不用搞个漫天纸花的游行之类的
I don't want a ticker tape parade or anything like that,
但你难道没有听到我刚才说的吗
but did you not just hear what I said?
哈维  这不是自杀式炸弹袭击那么简单
Listen, Javi. This is about more than a suicide vest.
疾控中心在斯通的公寓里发现了
The CDC turned up a lethal variant of the H5N1 virus
H5N1病毒的一个致命变种
in Stone's apartment.
这里是危险区域  斯通也被感染了
It's a hot zone. Stone's infected.
他周围的人估计也被感染了吧
And everyone around him might be, too.
我把门打开了  已经打开了
I got the door open! I got it!
把门关上  马上把门给我关上
Close that door! I said close it now!
所有人不许离开
Nobody leaves the train!
长官  埃斯波西托怎么样了
Sir, how is Esposito?
他和其他人都被转移到医院了
Well, he and the others were transported to the hospital,
-不过都被隔离观察了  -医生怎么说
- but they're in isolation. - What's the prognosis?
这个H5N1的病毒变种是致命的
Well, this particular strain of H5N1 is lethal
而且能通过空气接触传播
and can be spread through airborne contact.
不过是有疫苗的
But there is a vaccine.
疫苗也已经打给乘客们了
It's been given to the passengers,
即使接触过之后疫苗也能有效杀死病毒
and it can knock down the virus even after exposure.
那他应该没事了吧
So he's gonna be okay?
医生觉得问题不大
Doctors are optimistic.
疾控中心也在调查斯通过去的行踪
And the CDC is retracing Stone's steps
确认哪些人和他有过接触
to identify who else he was in contact with.
这家伙就像是个邪恶版的伤寒玛丽
This guy's like an evil version of Typhoid Mary.
自杀式炸弹背心  那些要求...
The suicide vest, the demands --
就是为了让人们接触病毒足够长时间
All about exposing people long enough
这样他们就能感染并传播病毒了
to get them infected so they'd spread the virus.
假如他真的去了研讨会或者歌剧院
Well, it could have been far worse
那情形就会糟糕多了
if he had made it to that seminar or the opera.
如此近距离跟那么多人接触
In proximity to all those people,
他会弄出一场瘟疫来的
he could have caused an epidemic.
可我还是不明白
But I-I-I'm still not clear.
那枪击案被害人和这些又有什么关系呢
How does our shooting victim fit into all this?
保罗·里夫斯之前正调查一个实验室
Paul Reeves was investigating the lab
那里有个H5N1的病毒样本丢失
where a sample of H5N1 went missing.
我们认为他发现斯通偷走了病毒
We think he figured out that Stone had stolen the virus,
正因为这个斯通才把他骗到公园  杀害了他
which is why Stone lured him into the park and killed him.
可是长官  这里仍然有很多问题
But, sir, there are still questions,
比如斯通在和谁合作
like who Stone was working with
他又是为什么要这么做
and why he did this in the first place,
我们需要找他谈谈
so we need to go and talk to him.
那你们得赶紧了
Well, you better hurry up
因为我听说他状况不太好
because I hear he's not in good shape.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你们不是牧师
You're not the priest.
不是  不过我也可以听你的忏悔
No, but I can take your confession.
我们知道你还有帮凶  斯通先生
We know you had help, Mr. Stone.
白色骑士  他是谁
White Knight, who is he?
他是几个月前我在"释放艾琳"网站
Someone I met through the "Free Erin" Site
认识的一个人
a few months back.
他的真名叫什么
What was his real name?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们因为艾琳结识
We bonded over Erin,
在想怎么把她救出来
over how to get her out.
他是个战略大师
He was a strategic thinker.
我不是  所以他帮我制定计划
I wasn't, so he helped me with the plan.
我是绝对不会引爆那件背心的
I never would have detonated that vest.
我只是...我只是需要一些谈判条件
I just -- - I just needed some leverage.
我爱艾琳
I love Erin.
我想要的仅仅是她的自由
All I wanted was to see her free.
我看你是更想让人们得病
More like you wanted to get people sick.
你在说什么
What do you mean?
你想通过传播致命病毒
You tried to start an epidemic
来制造一场瘟疫
by spreading your deadly virus.
艾琳的事只不过是个插曲罢了
Erin was just a sideshow.
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?
歌剧院  研讨会...
The opera, the seminar --
近距离接触权贵
hundreds of one-percenters in close proximity.
简直就是传播疾病绝佳场所
That was the perfect environment to spread your disease.
什...疾病
It -- disease?
不  我想找个能争取到艾琳的最佳场所
No, I -- I was - trying to find the best spot to take my stand for Erin.
那你为什么打电话给保罗·里夫斯
Then why did you call Paul Reeves?
白色骑士说那是计划中的一部分
White knight s-said - that it was part of the plan.
我...我打电话给里夫斯说在公园见面
I-I...Called Reeves to tell him about some meeting at the park.
我压根不知道他是谁
I didn't even know who he was.
那研讨会和歌剧院...
The seminar and the opera --
这些也是白色骑士的主意
Were those White Knight's ideas, too?
原来我被陷害了
So I was set up.
有人利用了我
Somebody used me.
我得的这个病...
This thing I have --
我也有可能传染给别人了
I may have given it to other people, too?
刚才的对话和我想象中的不一样
Okay, that is not how I imagined that conversation would go.
如果斯通说的是真的  那他就是替罪羊了
If Stone's telling the truth, then he's a fall guy.
他被利用了  成了装满病毒的容器
He was groomed, turned into a vector for the virus,
还被操纵传播病毒
and manipulated into spreading it.
这一切都和保罗·里夫斯的调查有关
Which means this all connects to Paul Reeves' investigation
就是那间储存病毒样本的实验室
of the lab where the virus came from.
斯通是被蓄意感染上的
Stone was deliberately infected.
疾控中心确认有人把他的哮喘吸入器
The CDC confirmed that someone turned his asthma inhaler
改造成了病毒传播工具
into a virus-delivery system.
问题是这是谁的主意
The question is, who came up with that idea?
答案肯定和这间保罗调查的实验室有关
The answer has got to be connected to this lab that Paul was investigating.
我也这么认为  贝克特  看看这个
I think it is. Beckett, take a look at this.
这间丢失病毒样本的实验...
The, uh, lab from which the virus went missing --
莱瑟姆制药  他们也正是
Uh, Latham Pharmaceuticals -- they're the same company
制造埃斯波和其他人用的疫苗的公司
that makes the vaccine that Espo and the others got.
这也是他们为什么会有H5N1样本的原因
Which is why they had samples of H5N1 in the first place.
没错  不过作为调查的一部分
Right, but as part of his investigation,
保罗也查了疫苗的生产订单
Paul was looking into production orders of the vaccine.
特别是这一单  整整1000万单位的疫苗
Specifically, this one for 10 million units of the vaccine.
卡塞尔  全世界只有1000个
Castle, there were only 1,000 reported cases
H5N1禽流感的通报病例
of H5N1 worldwide.
那莱瑟姆为什么突然要1000万疫苗呢
So why would Latham suddenly order up 10 million vaccines?
除非他们知道疫情要爆发了
Unless they knew that there was gonna be an outbreak.
我想保罗也有此疑问
I think Paul was asking the same question.
贾维斯女士  谢谢你抽空过来
Ms. Jarvis, thank you for taking the time.
当然
O-of course.
你们找到对保罗下毒手的人了吗
Yeah, d -- have you found whoever, uh, did this to Paul?
不  还没有  但我们确有几个问题想问你
No, not yet, but we do have a few questions.
你知道他为什么
Now, do you know
要调查莱瑟姆制药吗
why he was investigating Latham pharmaceuticals?
那是他的工作
It was his job.
用联邦政府的钱生产疫苗的公司
Companies that produce vaccines with federal money
都要受到总审计局的监管
are tracked by G.A.O.
而莱瑟姆制药生产了治疗一种
And Latham developed a vaccine
罕见却致命的病毒疫苗  对吗
for a rare but deadly flu virus, didn't they?
那种流感罕见到
I mean, a flu so rare
疫苗一直以来无用武之地
that the vaccine just sits on the shelf.
这种情况我们见得多了
Yeah, we see that a lot.
我们研制出防御型疫苗
Preventive vaccines are created,
但并不是所有的流感病毒都会蔓延
but not all flu strains become widespread.
-要是有人从中作梗就会蔓延  -你说什么
- Well, they do with a little help. - Excuse me?
你最近把所有资产都买了莱瑟姆的股票
You recently converted all of your assets to Latham stock.
为什么
Why is that?
我怎么投资跟你没关系
How I invest is none of your concern.
当你想要引起H5N1疫情  这件事就跟我有关
It became my concern when you tried to start an H5N1 epidemic.
你只需借助一个像杰瑞德·斯通
With the help of someone gullible,
好骗且容易掌控的人就行了
someone you could easily manipulate, like Jared Stone.
你在说什么啊
What on earth are you talking about?
我不认识什么杰瑞德·斯通
I d -- I don't know any Jared Stone.
你丈夫是把他女朋友艾琳·威尔逊
Your husband was one of the prosecutors
关进监狱的公诉人之一
who put away his girlfriend, Erin Wilson.
所以当你需要替罪羊时  你知道该找谁
So when you needed a patsy, you knew just where to look.
接下来当你的同事保罗
And then your colleague Paul,
发现那巨额的疫苗订单时  便开始调查
when he saw that huge vaccine order, he started digging.
当你发现他马上就要查到真相时
And when you saw that he was getting closer to the truth,
你就把他铲除了
you eliminated him.
这太荒唐了  你们无法证明这一切
That is absurd. You can't prove any of this.
实际上  我们可以
Actually, we can.
我们找到你在白色骑士云端账户下
We found the e-mails you wrote in your cloud account,
写的那些电子邮件了
under the username "White Knight."
我们还逮捕了跟你合谋的
We also arrested a Latham executive
一名莱瑟姆高层
with whom you were colluding.
他承认了自己的罪行  并与检察官达成了协议
He admitted to his role, and he cut a deal.
他把责任都推给你了
And he threw you under the bus.
你差点就让上千万人感染
You could have infected
并且丧命  贾维斯女士
and killed millions of people, Ms. Jarvis.
这一切
And for what,
就为了你能开上豪车住上豪宅吗
so you could drive a nicer car, buy a bigger house?
这一切难道就只为了钱吗
Was this all just because of money?
我要求请律师
I want a lawyer.
你最好找个好点的
You better find a good one.
我听说大家都可以出院了
So, I, uh -- I hear everybody's good to go.
都很健康
Clean bills of health.
昨天这个时候
This time yesterday,
得上流感是我们最不关心的问题
catching the flu - was the least of our problems.
你干得很不错
You did all right down there.
我才不管他们怎么说交通警呢
I don't care what they say about transit cops.
他们对警探也没说什么好话
What they say about gold shields is even worse --
因为那是实话实说
mostly 'cause it's true.
我们合作完美
We make a tight team.
在战斗中培养出来的感情  你明白的
Bonds forged in the heat of battle -- you know how it is.
是
Yeah.
我没跟你说实话
I wasn't straight with you.
我有个五岁的儿子
I have a 5-year-old son.
你说你没成家
Uh, you said that you didn't have a family.
为什么要隐瞒呢
Why hide that?
我不想让你因为我是个母亲而担心
I didn't want you worried about me being a mom down there.
你真是个人物  梅丽莎
You are a piece of work, Marisa.
莱妮是谁
Who's Lenny?
还是叫蕾妮
Or is it Lanie?
你怎么知道的
How do you know about her?
我上次任务中被简易爆炸装置炸坏了鼓膜
On my last tour, an I.E.D. blew out my eardrum.
所以我现在很会读唇语
Got pretty good at reading lips.
在你制住斯通前你念了她的名字
You were saying her name before you took down Stone.
我不  我不记得了
Yeah, I don't -- I don't remember that.
你在那个时刻想到的人  对你来说很重要
Who you think of - in that moment -- it has weight.
别用宝贵的东西去换取别的东西
Don't trade what's real for something that isn't.
回头见  哈维
I'll see you around, Javi.
我们可不是每天都能遇到这种
Well, it's not every day you come across someone
比人肉炸弹还可恨的人
who makes a suicide bomber look like the good guy.
我联系过医院了
So, I talked to the hospital.
杰瑞德·斯通会恢复的
Jared Stone will make a full recovery,
但显然他的麻烦还没完呢
though clearly his troubles aren't over yet.
是啊  除非他也能进艾琳·威尔逊所在的监狱
Yeah, unless he goes to the same prison as Erin Wilson,
因为说到底杰瑞德·斯通犯罪的动机
because in the end, Jared Stone was driven
是出于最原始的感情  爱
by the most primal of emotions -- love.
只不过他可以找个更妥当的方式来表达
Except he could have picked a better way to express it.
-看看谁来了  -你好吗
- Hey, look who's here. - What's up?
战无不胜的英雄万岁
Hail the conquering hero!
伙计  你可吓死我了
Man, you gave me a scare.
-那是因为你没胆  -好吧
- That's because you're a wimp. - Oh. Okay.
要是这么说的话  我也是没胆的人咯
Yeah, well, I guess that makes me a wimp, too.
还有我的份吗
Got any of that left over for me?
哈维  我都快吓死了  我还以为
Javi, I was worried sick. I thought --
我懂  但我好着呢
I know what you thought, but I'm here.
我回来了  我没事
I'm back. I'm all right.
我不想打断你们  但我有个好主意
I hate to interrupt, but I have a brilliant idea.
咱们去老地方怎么样
How about we all go to the Old Haunt, huh?
我请
Drinks on me.
走吧  咱们坐地铁去
Come on, we'll take the subway.
-太快了吗  -太快了
- Too soon? - Too soon.
请接受我的歉意
Please accept this as a token of my apology.
我是不是搭错线了
Am I on the wrong track, here?